let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: " Management is a social process means that:",
        answer: "C. it takes place through people.",
        options: [
            "A. it aims at achieving pre-determined objectives.",
            "B. it is influenced by various changes.",
            "C. it takes place through people.",
            "D. it is aided by computers."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: " Which of the following is not one of the old manager's practices?",
        answer: "B. working with and for group members.",
        options: [
            "A. making most decisions alone.",
            "B. working with and for group members.",
            "C. hiding information.",
            "D. considering himself as a boss or controller."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: " The formal study of management began as a part or reflection of the:",
        answer: "C. industrial revolution.",
        options: [
            "A. communication revolution.",
            "B. knowledge revolution.",
            "C. industrial revolution.",
            "D. Russian revolution."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: " The “Contemporary Developments School” focused on:",
        answer: "D. external environment.",
        options: [
            "A. work.",
            "B. workers.",
            "C. internal environment.",
            "D. external environment."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: " According to the “Classical School” assumptions:",
        answer: "C. man is rational and has his own financial and physical needs.",
        options: [
            "A. man is social and has his own psychological and social needs.",
            "B. any organization is considered as an open system.",
            "C. man is rational and has his own financial and physical needs.",
            "D. all of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: " One of the major criticisms of the “Behavioral School” is that it:",
        answer: "B. focused on internal variables of the organization and neglected variables of the external environment.",
        options: [
            "A. dealt with people as machines.",
            "B. focused on internal variables of the organization and neglected variables of the external environment.",
            "C. ignored the efficiency and power considerations inside the organization.",
            "D. considered financial incentives as the most important factor, which motivates people to perform their work."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: " Frederick Taylor is referred to as:",
        answer: "B. the father of scientific management.",
        options: [
            "A. the father of the modern management theory.",
            "B. the father of scientific management.",
            "C. the father of the human relations school.",
            "D. none of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: " Elton Mayo is referred to as:",
        answer: "C. the father of the human relations school.",
        options: [
            "A. the father of the modern management theory.",
            "B. the father of scientific management.",
            "C. the father of the human relations school.",
            "D. none of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: " The “Hawthorne” studies concluded that:",
        answer: "C. psychological incentives and type of supervision are very important.",
        options: [
            "A. there is an important need for teaching management.",
            "B. financial incentives are very important.",
            "C. psychological incentives and type of supervision are very important.",
            "D. management is a social process of decision making."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: " “(SWOT) Analysis” refers to:",
        answer: "C. both the internal and external environments scanning.",
        options: [
            "A. the internal environment scanning.",
            "B. the external environment scanning.",
            "C. both the internal and external environments scanning.",
            "D. none of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: " “Medium-term Planning” is called:",
        answer: "B. intermediate planning.",
        options: [
            "A. strategic planning.",
            "B. intermediate planning.",
            "C. operational planning.",
            "D. none of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: " One of the main characteristics of the effective goals and objectives is to be:",
        answer: "D. all of the above.",
        options: [
            "A. accurate.",
            "B. achievable.",
            "C. divisible.",
            "D. all of the above."
        ]
    },
    
];